SAMUEL RIVERA

https://samuelriverac.com samuelrivera64@gmail.com

Tel: +584262029204

FULL STACK ENGINEER with +3 years' experience, designing websites & developing web applications for tech companies, startups, and business to deliver successfully the functionalities of the app, appeal to clients, maintain their interest and loyalty to the brand, using Vue or React & Redux and frameworks like NextJS & Gatsby and integrate the back-end with either GraphQL or REST APIs. I also have experience with WordPress and PHP.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - OrinocoDEV - Part time (Remote) - Jun 2021 - Present

- Refactoring of old coding bases, and development of new features for different Web Apps, developed on Node and Vue
- Helping the junior OrinocoDev team to increase code quality and prevent large technical debts, also implemented Test driven development on their scrum methodology to boost productivity and code quality

Full Stack Developer - Freelancer - Full-time (Remote) - May 2018 - Present

- Worked with more than 15 clients from different parts of the world with different scopes and requirements such as:
 - o Design and developing themes and plugins on WordPress.
 - o Design, developing, and implementing React single page applications.
 - o Consulting about Web Marketing and SEO; and technical support.

Currently working part time as contractor at DevReady (NM, USA)

Frontend Developer - Orinoco.io - Full time (El Tigre, Venezuela) - May 2018 - Oct 2018

- Designed a decentralized crypto exchange, along with a 5 person team.
- Developed a Single-Page Application with Vue, Vuetify, and GraphQL.
- After 3 months of finishing the Project, The user base doubled to 4000 and has made more than 75000 transactions in the same period.

Full Stack Developer - PDVSA - Internship (El Tigre, Venezuela) - Feb 2018 - May 2018

- Analyzed of the user stories told by 10 members of the Company's Administration management, and designed the application accordingly.
- Developed a web app on CodeIgniter with PostgreSQL as database, according to the company's standards & methodologies, as explained by the software development team.
- Successfully implemented at the company's regional area of operations (Orinoco Oil Belt).

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio Website: React, Gatsby and Sass. (<u>samuelriverac.com</u>)

PayME Open banking PSD2 payment app Demo: AdonisJS, MySQL, React

Unnamed Job board Project: React, Redux, Next, AdonisJS and MySQL.

SKILLS

Back-end: PHP, Codeigniter, Laravel, Wordpress, Javascript, NodeJs, AdonisJs, ExpressJs.

Front-end: JQuery, React, Redux, NextJS, GatsbyJS, Vue, Vuex, NuxtJS.

Databases: Mysql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL.

Web design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass.

Tools: Git, Photoshop, Trello, Figma, Insomnia, Slack.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Systems Engineering

National Polytechnical Experimental University of the Armed Forces (UNEFA).